Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. David Faulkner papers RL.11443
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. David Faulkner papers
1925-1996 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
RL.11443
6.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London Office first opened in 1899. David Faulkner was an executive at JWT's London and New York offices. Includes correspondence, status reports, presentations, research reports and other printed materials. Companies represented include British Overseas Trade Board, British Standards Institution, Cancer Relief MacMillan Fund, Elida Gibbs, Scott Paper (Bowater Scott), St. Ivel and Vine Products. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: General Files; Account Files.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London Office first opened in 1899. David Faulkner was an executive at JWT's London and New York offices.
Biographical: Joined JWT London 1966 as Trainee. 1977 named Associate Director and Senior Account Representative. 1998 relocated to the U.S. as Worldwide Account Director for Kraft. 1999 returned to London as Director-in-Charge.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. David Faulkner papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office records; J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office advertisements; J. Walter Thompson Company International advertisements
Collection Overview
Includes correspondence, status reports, presentations, research reports and other printed materials. Companies represented include British Overseas Trade Board, British Standards Institution, Cancer Relief MacMillan Fund, Elida Gibbs, Scott Paper (Bowater Scott), St. Ivel and Vine Products. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- Great Britain; Advertising -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising executives -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain -- History; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Kraft Foods Company; Scott Paper Company; Pepsi-Cola Company
- General Files, 1946-1995 and undated; 1
  - Account Management Department, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Account Representatives Craft Skills, 1981; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Craft Skills Seminar, 1992 (Box 1)
  - JWT Common Investment Fund, 1995 (Box 1)
  - JWT Pension and Life Insurance Scheme, 1991-1995 and undated; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - JWT Pension Rules, 1991 (Box 1)
  - JWT Trustees Limited, 1995 (Box 1)
  - New business, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
  - Thompson Way of Total Branding, undated (Box 1)
  - Tom Cheney New Yorker cartoon, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Training materials, 1946-1994 and undated; 3 folders (Box 2)
- Account files, 1925-1996 and undated; 2
  - Akzo credentials pitch, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Amnesty International, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Ansells, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Batchelor's Food--Project Opus, 1987 (Box 2)
  - British Overseas Trade Board (BOTB), 1986-1988; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - British Standards Institution (BSI)--Advertising, 1995 (Box 3)
  - British Standards Institution (BSI)--Future Relevance of the Buyers Guide, 1994 (Box 3)
  - British Standards Institution (BSI)--International training, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - British Standards Institution (BSI)--Jobs in progress, 1995 (Box 3)
  - British Standards Institution (BSI)--Kitemark advertising, 1995 (Box 3)
  - British Standards Institution (BSI)--Marketing and budgeting, 1995 (Box 3)
  - British Standards Institution (BSI)--Newsletters and publications, 1995 (Box 3)
  - British Standards Institution (BSI)--Promotional budet 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - British Standards Institution (BSI)--Strategic planning presentation, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Cancer Relief Macmillan Fund (CRMF), 1993-1995; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Cancer Relief Macmillan Fund (CRMF)--Annual reviews, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Cancer Relief Macmillan Fund (CRMF)--Presentations, 1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Department of Transport--Road Safety campaign, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Development Trust, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Elida Gibbs--Progress report, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Elida Gibbs--Timotei, 1983-1990; 15 folders (Box 4)
  - InSitu, undated (Box 4)
  - Kraft--The Big Chill, undated (Box 4)
  - Kraft--Brand Equity Program, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Kraft--Brand Plus Strategy, undated (Box 5)
  - Kraft--Dairylea, undated (Box 5)
  - Kraft--Dairylea and Philadelphia advertising, undated (Box 11)
  - Kraft--Kenco coffee, 1993-1996 and undated; 7 folders (Box 5)
  - Kraft--Kenco coffee, 1996 (Box 11)
  - Kraft--Kraft Food Management Group, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Kraft--Kraft Jacobs Suchard coffee, 1995-1996 and undated; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Kraft--Kraft Jacobs Suchard coffee, 1995 (Box 11)
  - Kraft--Kraft Singles, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Kraft--Mellow Bird, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Kraft--Project BMW (Miracle Whip), 1994 (Box 5)
  - Kraft--Project BMW (Miracle Whip), 1994-1995; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Kraft--Qualitative Research into Miracle Whip, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Kraft--UK Status of Miracle Whip, 1995 (Box 6)
  - Kraft--Vintage advertising (prepared for Kraft/JWT 70th anniversary in the UK), 1925-1938 (Box 6)
  - Kraft--Worldwide Kraft Products and Consumer Trends, undated (Box 6)
  - Pepsi, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Royal Hospital and Home, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Royal Hospital and Home, undated (Box 11)
  - Scott Paper, 1986-1993; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Scott Paper, 1992-1995; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Scott Paper--Andrex: A Look at Velvet and Drixcell, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Scott Paper--Andrex Moist Toilet Tissue, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Scott Paper--Bowater Scott, 1979-1993; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Scott Paper--Bowater Scott, 1986-1987 (Box 8)
  - Scott Paper--Brand Book, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Scott Paper--Client agency reviews, 1987-1989 (Box 8)
  - Scott Paper--Correspondence, 1988; 9 folders (Box 8)
  - Scott Paper--Correspondence, 1988-1994 and undated; 6 folders (Box 9)
  - Scott Paper--Correspondence, 1988 (Box 11)
  - Scott Paper--Europe/International, 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - Scott Paper--"Green" marketing, 1989-1990; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Scott Paper--"Green" marketing, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
  - Scott Paper--Media, 1991-1993 (Box 9)
  - Scott Paper--Press, 1993 (Box 10)
  - Scott Paper--Press, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Scott Paper--Worldwide Scott Management Meeting, 1994 (Box 10)
  - St. Ivel--Gold strategy, 1984-1991; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - St. Ivel--Yellow fats marketing, 1991 (Box 10)
  - St. Ivel--Yogurt/Desserts, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Vine Products--Warninks Advocaat, 1986-1987; 3 folders (Box 10)